Guide to the Lisa Carver archive, 1989-1999.
Carver, Lisa archive
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Lisa Carver archive, 1989-1999.
8497
Carver, Lisa.
.3 cubic foot.
Correspondence, diaries, manuscripts, movie film, audio recordings, newspapers, computer media, photographs, Printed material, and publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Periodicals, pasteups, proofs, ephemera, audiotapes, and a videotape, documenting Carver's work, life, and interests. Includes a complete run of Rollerderby (issues 1-25), as well as preliminary pasteups, proofs, artwork, and photographs for use in the zine. Also, ephemera and poster artwork for an issue of the zine Generation L, Suckdog and other projects; eight cassette tapes of music or performance sounds; and a VHS videotape containing a rough cut of the work Anatomically correct and Lisa Carver's laptop.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
American stage and recording artist, author, and publisher, the editor of the zine Rollerderby and member of the band Suckdog. Her work spans the worlds of publishing, art, transgressive sex, and gender politics and performance. In Roller Derby, Carver and her friends interview bands and other celebrities; the zine also includes comics, illustrations, games, and letters to the editor.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Periodicals, pasteups, proofs, ephemera, audiotapes, and a videotape, documenting Carver's work, life, and interests. Includes a complete run of Rollerderby (issues 1-25), as well as preliminary pasteups, proofs, artwork, and photographs for use in the zine. Also, ephemera and poster artwork for an issue of the zine Generation L, Suckdog and other projects; eight cassette tapes of music or performance sounds; and a VHS videotape containing a rough cut of the work Anatomically correct.
Lisa Carver's diaries, notebooks, additional photographs, correspondence including letters from Bill Callahan of Smog and Boyd Rice, material documenting the fanzine Dirt, and Lisa Carver's laptop from 2006.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Carver, Lisa.; Carver, Lisa.; Suckdog (Musical group)
Titles:
Rollerderby.; Generation L.; Dirt.
Subjects:
Zines -- Publishing.; Avant-garde (Music); Erotic art
Form and Genre Terms:
Fanzines.; Printed ephemera.; Audiocassettes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Suckdog, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Tipper Gore, "Rape G. G." lyrics, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- "Why Miss World?, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Rollerderby, 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Paste-ups, proofs, etc..., n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Rough cut - Anatomically Correct [VHS tape], n.d.; V-7209 (Box 1)
- Eight cassette tapes of music and performance sounds, n.d.; tr-10513-10520 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, ca. 1989-1998 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Magazines with articles regarding Lis Carver, 1995, 2000, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Newspapers with articles regarding Lisa Carver, 1998-2005 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- WWE program with signatures, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  -Ryback, Hornswoggle, an unknown signature on the front cover and 3 other unknowns on the autograph page
- Photographs, diaries, notebooks and other writings, ca. 1959-1999 (Box 3)
- Lisa Carver's laptop, ca. 2006; HD-4 (Box 4)